DANIEL MCINTYRE

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with front-end skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and cloud-based database storage systems such as Firebase, in addition to knowledge of back-end server building with Node JS, Express and MongoDB. I build the responsive and accessible websites and applications of tomorrow. My passion for finding solutions to problems as well as leading and managing teams is highlighted through my decade of experience in previous strategic communication-based roles.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- SASS
- REST APIs
- React
- ReduxFirebase

- Node JS
- Express
- MongoDB
- Bootstrap
- Material UI
- SendGrid
- Stripe
- Heroku

- Netlify
- Git
- GitHub
- Command Line
- · Responsive Design
- Team Building, Training and Development
- Leadership & Communication

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology, Toronto, ON

Web Development Bootcamp and JavaScript Fundamentals, November 2021 – April 2022

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON

Bachelor of Arts, Media Studies, 2008 - 2013

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Socialite

<u>LIVE</u> <u>REPO</u> React | Firebase |

Node JS

A full-stack event planning app built with React in the front-end and Node JS/firebase in the back-end.

Video Diary

LIVE REPO
REST API | Firebase | React

Utilizes YouTube's REST API and firebase database to fetch and search videos based on the user's search query. Users can also save and delete their videos.

Giphy Sentiment

LIVE REPO REST API | Firebase | React

Utilizes Giphy's API and firebase database to fetch and search Giphy's based on the user's search query. Users can also save their Giphy's.

Movie Mood

LIVE REPO REST API | HTML | CSS

Utilizes the Movie Database API to fetch movies based on genre and time-period.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Co. Lab, Lead Software Developer, May 2022 - Present

• Lead Application Developer in shipping a product in collaboration with a cross-functional team.

College of the Kinesiologists of Ontario, Manager of Communications May 2021 - October 2021

Managed all internal and external communications material and media, including website.

Patients Canada, Manager of Communications, March 2016 – December 2020

• Responsible for the re-development of Patient's Canada's website, including implementing front and back-end features. Also managed the CiviCRM database system.

Grosso McCarthy Inc., Manager of Client Services, March 2016- December 2020

• Lead, trained and directed the Communications team and developed client proposals leading to acquisition of new clients for the firm.

Office of the Federal Minister of Health, Communications Assistant, Sept 2014 - December 2015

Developed and executed media strategies, including implementing social media campaigns.